Finding Aid to the Gloria Steinem papers SSC.MS.00237
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, 1946-96
  - Birthday celebrations and tributes
    - 50th, 1984
      - Scrapbook from Edie Van Horn (includes photo of Van Horn and Steinem; also letter by Van Horn defending Steinem against Redstockings allegations) (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - 60th: greetings, remarks by John Kenneth Galbraith, pledges to the Ms. Foundation for Women, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
  - Awards, honorary degrees and gifts: certificates, plaques, sculptures, statuettes, 1958-97
    - Awards and gifts, 1958-97; undated (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
      [see also SERIES X. OVERSIZE]
    - Food and Agriculture Organization Ceres Medal: correspondence and miscellany, 1974-76 (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
    - William O. Douglas, Public Counsel, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Honorary degrees, 1976-93 (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
  - Memorabilia
    - Autographed books
      - Polly Devlin, All of Us There (London), 1983 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Vicky Draham, I Think I May Paint the House in August (Olympia), 1976 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Daisy Fields, A Woman's Guide to Moving Up in Business and Government (Englewood Cliffs, NJ), 1983 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Stanley Friedman, The Magnificent Kennedy Women (Derby, CT), 1964 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Dan Greenburg and Suzanne O'Malley, How to Avoid Love and Marriage (New York), 1983 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Natasha Josefowitz, In A Nutshell: Feminist Verse (San Diego), 1981 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - David Rogers, Poetry and Other Interface, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Sharinne Strickland Weiller, Madam President (New York), 1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Anne Wittels and Ivy Bottini, Ms.Ery (Beverly Hills), 1973 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Wonder Woman: A Ms. Book (New York) (includes introduction by Steinem and interpretive essay by Phyllis Chesler. Autograph by Elizabeth H Marston, widow of Wonder Woman creator William Moulton Maston), 1972 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Flo Kennedy, Color Me Flo: My Hard Life and Good Times, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - General: buttons, patches, poems, posters, and keepsakes (includes Steinem's war ration book, a stamp from office of Cesar Chavez, and Smith College Senior Banquet poem), 1954-83; undated (Box 30, Folder 3-8)
  - Family
    - Leo Steinem: legal papers and correspondence relating to his death, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Ruth Nuneviller Steinem
      - General correspondence (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Clippings from Ruth for Steinem's project, "The Crook Book" a/k/a "The Death Book,", 1963-64; undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Condolence letters on Ruth's death, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Memorial service program, obituaries, etc. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Pauline Steinem: article on suffrage, 1910 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Suzanne Steinem Patch: clippings, 1946; 1949; undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Robert Patch: clippings, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Other family members: correspondence, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 9)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE, 1954-97
  This series, the largest in Steinem's papers, comprising four sizeable subseries - General, Public response mail, Individuals, and Subjects -- is best described in the words of Mary Barton, Steinem's assistant in the mid-1980s, who wrote correspondents that "Ms. Steinem welcomes news, suggestions and words of advice from readers and friends," an apt description of the kinds of materials Steinem received. Every week, Steinem's office received book galleys with requests for blurbs or endorsements; manuscripts with requests for comment, if not introductions or forewords; manuscripts, film scripts or articles along with requests for advice or help in bringing them to fruition; requests for public appearances; letters from people she met at book signings, speeches, or other places; letters from people responding to her public appearances and writings, with either gratitude for or hostility toward her political positions, and/or general advice about her personal appearance; pleas for help and/or financial assistance; and letters from the mentally ill. Many individuals sent letters of appreciation for her words in print, on television, and in personal appearances. They also sent in newspaper articles and advertisements that outraged them, photographs of themselves, court documents when seeking her assistance in legal matters, promotional materials for businesses and service groups, cassette tapes of songs they had written and/or recorded about the feminist movement, videotapes of themselves, and so forth. This large volume of mail generally falls into two large subseries -- General correspondence and Public response mail. The other subseries contain correspondence with particular "Individuals," and a small amount of correspondence on particular Subjects.
  Researchers should be aware that the lines between the General correspondence and the Public response mail are not distinct. In part, the difficulty in distinguishing between public-response mail and more "professional" and "personal" correspondence, especially and even until the mid-1980s, reflects the state of the feminist project, activists and authors working out of their homes, launching initiatives without letterhead, and so forth. Couple that with the blurring of personal and professional relationships, and the general effect Steinem had of making relative strangers feel as if they were among her close circle of friends, makes it sometimes difficult to discern focused fan-mail from chatty professional mail. As a general rule, letters specifically responding to public appearances or writings by Steinem are housed with public response mail, and all other correspondence filed as general correspondence. For example, requests for autographs from individual admirers are filed with the Public response mail, while requests for autographs from organizations planning fundraisers are filed with the General correspondence. Requests for interviews or meetings from professional journalists are filed under General correspondence, while similar requests from hopeful amateurs are filed under Public response mail. In many cases, copies of Steinem's reply, drafted either personally or by an assistant in consultation with Steinem, are attached.
  Early material in the General correspondence pertains to her trip to India, and her business activities there. Her nascent career as a journalist is also documented in correspondence between Steinem and editors at various New York publications. After the founding of Ms. Magazine in 1971, much of the general correspondence pertains to the readership and business of the magazine, and, later, of the Ms. Foundation. As Steinem became a public figure, correspondence pertains to the possibility of securing Steinem for a public appearance, or requests Steinem's support for various organizations, from simple endorsement and/or advice to help with fundraising to serving on a board.
  Public response mail consists of letters from Steinem's admirers and detractors, generally from men and women unknown to her, or whom she met while traveling. Television appearances generated a large volume of mail; for example, Steinem was generally flooded with letters after appearances on the popular Phil Donahue Show, and so weeks after those appearances (e.g. Spring 1978, January 1980, Fall 1983) are filled with viewer commentary. Similarly, 1977 correspondence contains many listener responses to Steinem's Spectrum commentaries; 1986 correspondence includes viewer responses to Steinem's work on the Today Show; 1984-85 correspondence contains responses to both the television movie based on "A Bunny's Tale" and an accompanying article Steinem published in T.V. Guide.
  Similar material arrived after Steinem's public speaking engagements and following the publication of books and articles. An interesting group of letters in 1993, 1994 and 1995 respond to two articles by Steinem translated into Russian; subsequently, Steinem received inquiries from men and women in the former Soviet Union seeking advice on a range of topics from marriage to and adoption by U.S. citizens to how to advance the women's movement in Russia. (A book-length manuscript, written in Russian, was sent to Steinem; this is how housed in the Countries Collection of the Sophia Smith Collection).
  The authors of these letters also include aspiring writers, filmmakers, entrepreneurs, as well as many others in search of professional advice. Included are the many requests for help Steinem received from women who had seen Steinem speak or read her work and thought she might be able to help with a host of personal problems, from sexual harassment in the workplace to the effects of divorce to child custody issues and so forth. It was those sorts of letters that eventually prompted Steinem to co-found the Women's Action Alliance (whose records are also held by the Sophia Smith Collection). Because Steinem and her assistants took such queries very seriously, and responded to them in many cases as they would queries from colleagues and professionals, it is occasionally difficult to distinguish unknown readers from friends and colleagues.
  Another large category of mail in this series comes from eccentric and/or mentally or emotionally disturbed correspondents. Steinem labeled this "crazy mail," alerting her staff to them in the event that the writer might become dangerous. In some cases, dozens of letters were mailed in a short period of time by a single writer and deposited to the Sophia Smith Collection unopened; in these cases, a sampling was retained and the remainder discarded.
  More than 200 folders, arranged alphabetically by surname, comprise the series pertaining to "Individuals." These files in general reproduce Steinem's own, though additional files have been created for other significant correspondents identified during processing. They are distinguished from the files pertaining to individuals in SERIES VII. SUBJECTS in that they are wholly or primarily correspondence to and from the individuals, whereas the subject files are wholly or primarily materials about the individual (for political figures, see also SERIES VI. POLITICAL CAMPAIGNS). Occasionally, however, there is both a subject file and a correspondence file for an individual; researchers interested in an individual should check both series for an individual's appearances throughout this finding aid. Given the variety of assistants who aided Steinem and the difficulty in maintaining a single filing system over the years, the presence or absence of a separate correspondence file cannot be interpreted as an indicator of a correspondent's significance.
  Finally, a small amount of correspondence is gathered into a small subseries by Subject. This includes letters of recommendation and correspondence pertaining to the depositing of Steinem's papers in the Sophia Smith Collection.
  - General
    - 1954-69 (Box 32, Folder 1-17)
    - 1970-72 (Box 33, Folder 1-12)
    - 1973-77 (Box 34, Folder 1-22)
    - 1978-Sep 1979 (Box 35, Folder 1-14)
    - Oct 1979-1980 (Box 36, Folder 1-15)
    - 1981-Jul 1982 (Box 37, Folder 1-13)
    - Aug 1982-Mar 1983 (Box 38, Folder 1-10)
    - Apr-Oct 1983 (Box 39, Folder 1-8)
    - Nov 1983-Feb 1984 (Box 40, Folder 1-7)
    - Feb-May 1984 (Box 41, Folder 1-6)
    - Jun-Oct 1984 (Box 42, Folder 1-7)
    - Oct 1984-Feb 1985 (Box 43, Folder 1-8)
    - Mar-Dec 1985 (Box 44, Folder 1-10)
    - 1986-87 (Box 45, Folder 1-12)
    - 1988-Sep 1990 (Box 46, Folder 1-13)
    - Oct 1990-91 (Box 47, Folder 1-12)
    - Jan-Nov 1992 (Box 48, Folder 1-11)
    - Dec 1992-Mar 1993 (Box 49, Folder 1-8)
    - Mar-Sep 1993 (Box 50, Folder 1-8)
    - Oct 1993-Jun 1994 (Box 51, Folder 1-9)
    - Jun 1994-Apr 1995 (Box 52, Folder 1-12)
    - May 1995-Jun 1996 (Box 53, Folder 1-11)
    - Jul 1996-May 1997 (Box 54, Folder 1-10)
    - Jun-Dec 1997, undated (Box 54A, Folder 1-7)
  - Public response
    - 1964-73 (Box 55, Folder 1-10)
    - 1974-79 (Box 56, Folder 1-8)
    - 1970s-Feb 1983 (Box 57, Folder 1-8)
    - Mar-Sep 1983 (Box 58, Folder 1-18)
    - Sep-Dec 1983 (Box 59, Folder 1-7)
    - Dec 1983-Mar 1984 (Box 60, Folder 1-7)
    - Mar-Jun 1984 (Box 61, Folder 1-8)
    - Jun-Sep 1984 (Box 62, Folder 1-9)
    - Oct-Dec 1984 (Box 63, Folder 1-7)
    - 1984 undated-Feb 1985 (Box 64, Folder 1-9)
    - Mar-Dec 1985 (Box 65, Folder 1-9)
    - 1986-88 (Box 66, Folder 1-11)
    - 1989-Jan 1992 (Box 67, Folder 1-9)
    - Jan-Mar 1992 (Box 68, Folder 1-7)
    - Mar-Jun 1992 (Box 69, Folder 1-7)
    - Jun-Nov 1992 (Box 70, Folder 1-8)
    - Nov 1992-Jan 1993 (Box 71, Folder 1-7)
    - Jan-Feb 1993 (Box 72, Folder 1-7)
    - Feb-Apr 1993 (Box 73, Folder 1-7)
    - Apr-Aug 1993 (Box 74, Folder 1-8)
    - Aug-Dec 1993 (Box 75, Folder 1-9)
    - Jan-May 1994 (Box 76, Folder 1-7)
    - May-Jul 1994 (Box 77, Folder 1-8)
    - Jul-Oct 1994 (Box 78, Folder 1-7)
    - Nov 1994-Mar 1995 (Box 79, Folder 1-7)
    - Apr-Dec 1995 (Box 80, Folder 1-8)
    - Jan-Oct 1996 (Box 81, Folder 1-9)
    - Nov 1996-May 1997 (Box 82, Folder 1-9)
    - Jun-Dec 1997, 1990s (Box 83, Folder 1-9)
  - Individuals
    - Abou-Saif, Laila, 1978-84 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Abzug, Bella, 1989; 1993; undated (Box 84, Folder 2)
      [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS-Women USA]
    - Adams, Amy Goldstein 1992-93 [restricted] (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Alda, Alan and Arlene, 1980-86; undated (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Alpert, Jane, 1977-78 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Amram, David, 1967 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Andrews, Julie, 1965; 1992 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Anguiano, Lupe, 1977-78 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Arditti, Rita, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Asimov, Isaac, 1985 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Astor, Brooke, 1984 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Atkinson, Ti-Grace, 1971; 1974 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Barry, Kathleen, 1978-79 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Beare, Nikki, 1977; 1979 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Beatty, Warren, 1978 (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - de Beauvoir, Simone, 1974-80 (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1965 (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - Benton, Robert, 1984; undated (Box 84, Folder 18)
    - Bergen, Candice, 1978 (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - Bhavnani, Ishwar, 1954-59 (Box 84, Folder 20)
    - Berresford, Susan, 1979 (Box 84, Folder 21)
    - Bingham, Sallie, 1986-90 (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Bernstein, Leonard, undated (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Bird, Caroline 1968-92 (includes transcript of interview with Charlotte Bunch) (Box 84, Folder 24)
      [for Steinem's review of Born Female, see SERIES IV. WRITINGS-Articles-Book reviews]
    - Black, Cathleen, 1989 (Box 84, Folder 25)
    - Blankenship, Jayne, 1981; 1992 (Box 84, Folder 26)
    - Blechmen, Bob, undated (Box 84, Folder 27)
    - Bode, Janet, 1983 (Box 84, Folder 28)
    - Bottini, Ivy, 1983 (Box 84, Folder 29)
    - Bradlee, Benjamin, 1977 (Box 84, Folder 30)
    - Braudy, Susan, undated (Box 84, Folder 31)
    - Brinkley, David, 1969 (Box 84, Folder 32)
    - Brokaw, Tom, undated (Box 84, Folder 33)
    - Brown, Bert, 1982-83 (Box 84, Folder 34)
    - Brown, Helen Gurley, 1982; 1985; 1989; undated (Box 84, Folder 35)
      [see also SERIES III. SPEECHES AND APPEARANCES-In Conversation With....]
    - Brown, Rita Mae, 1973-78; undated (Box 85, Folder 1-3)
      [see also SERIES IV. WRITINGS-Wilson Center]
    - Brown, Tina, undated (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Brownmiller, Susan, 1974 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Broner, Esther, 1978-79 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Buckley, Gail L., 1989 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Burnett, Carol, 1984 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Burnett, Patricia Hill, 1977; undated (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Byrne, Jane, 1980 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Carbine, Pat and Tom, 1976; undated (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Card, Emily 1983-89 (includes transcript of interview with Steinem about women and finances and Steinem's own financial practices) (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Carroll, Connie, 1977; 1982; undated (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Carter, Jimmy, Rosalyn, and Judy Langford Carter, 1976-77; undated (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Chavez, Bernadette (aka Carmela), 1977; 1982; 1992 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Chavez, Cesar, 1968 (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Chesler, Phyllis 1970-84 (includes writings) (Box 85, Folder 17-18)
    - Chicago, Judy, 1992 (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - Chisholm, Shirley, 1978 (Box 85, Folder 29)
    - Chotzinoff, Blair (includes letter from daughter Marina), 1969-83; undated (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Clark, Dick, 1977 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Clayburgh, Jill, 1980 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Clinton, Hillary, 1997 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Clinton, William Jefferson, 1994 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Collins, Judy, 1989; undated (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Conyers, John, 1981 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Cook, Connie, 1978 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Corea, Gena, 1983 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Cowan, Belinda, 1979; undated (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Crawford, Joan, 1985 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - de Crow, Karen, 1977-80 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Cuomo, Mario, 1983 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Dellums, Ron, 1983 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Diller, Barry, 1980 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Donahue, Phil, 1978; 1986 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Douglas, Susan, undated (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - Dunlop, Joan, 1977-79 (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - Durant, Will, 1980 (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - Dworkin, Andrea, 1977-81 (Box 86, Folder 20)
    - Edelman, Marian Wright, 1985 (Box 86, Folder 21)
    - Edgar, Joanne, 1974; undated (Box 86, Folder 22)
    - Eikenberry, Jill, undated (Box 86, Folder 23)
    - Eisenstein, Zillah, 1983 (Box 86, Folder 24)
    - Farrell, Amy, 1990 (Box 86, Folder 25)
    - Farrell, Warren, 1977-79 (Box 86, Folder 26)
    - Farenthold, Sissy, 1982; 1984 (Box 86, Folder 27)
    - Fasteau, Brenda Feigen, 1973; 1985-86 (Box 86, Folder 28)
    - Felker, Clay, undated (Box 86, Folder 29)
    - Ferraro, Geraldine, 1985 (Box 86, Folder 30)
    - Fisher, Jane O'Reilly, 1964-66; undated (Box 86, Folder 31)
    - Flynt, Larry, 1977 (Box 86, Folder 32)
    - Fonda, Jane, 1982; 1993 (Box 86, Folder 33)
    - Ford, Betty and Gerald, 1974; 1976; 1980; undated (Box 86, Folder 34)
    - Fowler, Linda, 1975 (Box 86, Folder 35)
    - Fraser, Arvonne S., 1976 (Box 86, Folder 36)
    - Frederick, Peter, 1961; 1963; undated (Box 86, Folder 37)
    - Freeman, Jo, 1993; 1996 (Box 86, Folder 38)
    - Freeman, Robert, 1988 (Box 86, Folder 39)
    - French, Marilyn, 1989 (Box 86, Folder 40)
    - Fridenberg, Walter, 1958-60; undated (Box 86, Folder 41)
    - Friedan, Betty, 1986 (Box 86, Folder 42)
    - Fritz, Leah, 1977-90 (Box 86, Folder 43)
    - Frost, David, undated (Box 86, Folder 44)
    - von Furstenberg, Diane, 1979 (Box 86, Folder 45)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1964-88 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Gallagher, Patricia, 1983; 1987 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Gamache, Tom, 1990-95; undated (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - George, Phyllis, undated (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Gere, Richard, 1988 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Gifford, Kathy Lee, undated (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Ginsberg, Allen, 1969 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Ginsberg, Ruth, 1976-77 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Goodman, Emily, 1983; 1990 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Gould, Lois, 1979 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Graham, Katherine, 1977-82 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Green, Rayna, n.d (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Greer, Germaine, 1972; 1977 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Hack, Nadine, 1990 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Hamill, Pete, undated (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Harriman, Pamela, 1993 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Harrington, Michael, 1980-84; undated (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Hefner, Christie, 1980 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - Henderson, Skitch, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - Hepburn, Katharine, 1980 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Hernandez, Aileen, 1990 (Box 87, Folder 21)
      [see also "White House Conference on Families, 1979-80" in SERIES III. SPEECHES AND APPEARANCES]
    - Heyn, Dalma, 1994 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - Hochman, Sandra 1977, 1990, undated (includes photograph) (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - Holtzman, Elizabeth 1986 (includes clippings and speech, "Legal Inequality of Women: Marital Rape and Domestic Violence") (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Horbal, Koryne, 1988; 1990 (Box 87, Folder 25)
    - Hughes, Dorothy Pitman, 1983; undated (Box 87, Folder 26)
      [see also SERIES III. SPEECHES AND APPEARANCES-1972 for speaking itineraries]
    - Hume, Ellen, 1988 (Box 87, Folder 27)
    - Hunt, Helen, 1990-96; undated (Box 87, Folder 28)
    - Iacocca, Lee, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Johnson, Germaine 1985 (includes writings) (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Jones, Jenny, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Jong, Erica, 1980; 1989-90; undated (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Jordan, Hamilton, 1977 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Jordan, Vernon, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Kennedy, Edward and Joan, 1983-84; 1987 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Kennedy, Florynce, 1973; 1984; 1995 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Kennedy, Robert, 1965 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Kenyon, Dorothy, 1971 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Kesten, Robert, 1987-88 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - King, Billie Jean, 1974 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - King, Carole, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - King, Coretta Scott, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Kingston, Maxine Hong, 1977; undated (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1971 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - Koch, Ed, 1970-71 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Knowles, Marjorie Fine, 1982; undated (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - Kunstler, William, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - Kyoko, Michichita, 1979; 1983-86; 1990 (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - Lamm, Dottie 1983-84 (includes autographed copy of Second Banana) (Box 88, Folder 21)
    - Laredo (a/k/a Lara Dale), 1991 (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - Lauper, Cyndi, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - Laura X, 1975; 1981-82 (Box 88, Folder 24)
    - Lerner, Gerda, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 25)
    - Lewis, Jane, 1971-73 (Box 88, Folder 26)
    - Lindsay, John and Mary, 1966; 1971; undated (Box 88, Folder 27)
    - Lippert, Karin, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 28)
    - Locke, Sondra, 1994; undated (Box 88, Folder 29)
    - Love, Barbara, 1973 (Box 88, Folder 30)
    - MacKinnon, Catharine 1982, undated (includes draft of libel section, amicus brief for Andrea Dworkin) (Box 88, Folder 31)
    - Manchester, Melissa, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 32)
    - Mankiller, Wilma, 1989; undated (Box 88, Folder 33)
    - Marchiano, Linda, 1982 (Box 88, Folder 33)
    - Mason, Marsha, undated (Box 88, Folder 34)
    - McCorvey, Norma, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 35)
    - McGovern, George, 1997 (Box 88, Folder 36)
    - McKuen, Rod, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 37)
    - Millett, Kate, 1977; 1980; 1990 (Box 88, Folder 38)
    - Najimy, Kathy, 1990 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Navratilova, Martina, 1980 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Nessim, Barbara, 1967-90 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Newton, Verne, 1960s-70s (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Newman, Paul, 1968 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Nixon, Richard (from Steinem), 1970 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Norman, Jessye, 1992; undated (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1966; 1978; 1980 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Ono, Yoko, 1990; undated (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Orsag, Carol, 1980 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Painter, Nell, 1981; undated (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Paris, Ronnie, 1982 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Parrent, Joanne, 1983 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - de Passe, Suzanne, 1983 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Peacock, Mary, 1971 (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Pogrebin, Letty Cottin, 1980; 1982; 1992 (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Pottinger, Stan, 1979; undated (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Radziwill, Lee, 1967-68 (Box 89, Folder 18)
      [see also SERIES IV. WRITINGS- article research files]
    - Rather, Dan, 1982 (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - Reagan, Nancy, 1991 (Box 89, Folder 20)
    - Reasoner, Harry (Box 89, Folder 21)
    - Reddy, Helen, 1987 (Box 89, Folder 22)
    - Redford, Robert, 1986 (Box 89, Folder 23)